The Literature Club is a female-dominated society.
文芸部は女社会だ
I'm the only male first-year student.
1年生に男子は俺1人
They say that when three people gather, factions can form.
3人集まれば派閥が できるなんて話もあるが
In the case of the Literature Club,
文芸部の場合は
I feel like it's divided between me and everyone else.
俺と俺以外に 別れている気がする
Hey, Nukumizu-kun, hurry up and come over here!
おい温水（ぬくみず）君 早くおいでよ
What's wrong? If you're tired, I can give you a piggyback ride.
どうしたの？ 疲れたんならおぶってあげる
D-don't dawdle!
もう ぼ、ぼやぼやするな
I-if you let your guard down, you'll die.
ゆ、油断すると死ぬぞ
Today, I'm here at Nonhoi Park with the four first-year members of the Literature Club.
そう 今日俺は 文芸部の1年生4人でのんほいパークに来ている
We came to take photos for the website, but...
ホームページの写真を 撮りに来たのだが
...there's a reason we all came here together.
わざわざ全員で来たのには 理由がある
The number of views.
写真のアクセス数だ
Numbers can be cruel.
数字は残酷だ
If a hierarchy forms among the three of them, cracks in their friendship will form!
3人の間に順番ができれば 友情に亀裂が入るのは間違いない
For now, I'm just winging it, but...
今は適当にごまかしているが
...the day when they learn the truth isn't too far off.
こいつらが真実にたどり着く日も そう遠くはないだろう
That's why I'll upload a picture of the three of them together on the website, and fool them a little longer.
だからこそ 3人一緒の写真をホームページにアップして
Hey, Nukumizu-kun.
ねえ温水君
Happy-chan the sun bear was so cute, wasn't she?
マレーグマのハッピーちゃん 可愛かったよね
Even though she's all alone as a girl,
女の子一人きりにも関わらず
She's so lively and admirable.
元気にはしゃいで健気だよ
You really feel a sense of sympathy.
シンパシー感じちゃうね
Speaking of which, I heard a male sun bear arrived recently.
そういやば最近 オスのマレーグマが来たってさ
It wasn't out today, but it seems like they're getting along well.
今日は外に出てなかったけど 仲良くやってるらしいぞ
Oh.
え
I see...
そうなんだ…
Happy-chan has a boyfriend...
ハッピーちゃん彼氏いるんだ
I thought she was like me, but I've been betrayed.
仲間だと思ってたのに裏切られた
Yanami, you're getting kind of weird.
八奈見（やなみ） なんか変なモードに突入したぞ
It's best to just leave this alone.
これはそっとしておくに限る
Um,
えっと
Yakishio, which animal did you like best?
焼塩（やきしお）は どの動物がよかった？
Hmm...
うーん
I liked the African dormice at the nocturnal animal exhibit.
夜行性動物館の アフリカヤマネがよかったな
Oh, do you?
おっ わかるか？
Dormice are cute, aren't they?
やっぱヤマネは可愛いよな
Those little guys scurry around in the dark, don't they?
あの子たちって暗い中を ちょこまかと動き回るでしょ
When you watch them, your eyes gradually get used to it, but...
じっと観察してると どんどん目が慣れてくるけど
You stop wanting to fight them because of how cute they are.
愛着が湧いてきて 戦う気にならないんだよね
Animals aren't our enemies, okay?
動物は敵じゃないからな
Speaking of the nocturnal animal exhibit, the aardvark was cute, right?
夜行性動物館なら 土豚も可愛かっただろ
Y-you like aardvarks too?
お、お前も つ、土豚のよさ分かったか
After watching that nose twitch for about five minutes,
あの鼻の動きを 5分くらい眺めてたら
It kind of makes you forget everyday struggles and feel relaxed.
なんか日常の辛いことも忘れて 気分がゆったりしてきてさ
I-I could watch them for 10 minutes...
じゅ、10分続けるわ
W-watch it jump!
と、跳ぶぞ
Seriously? Aardvarks are amazing.
マジか 土豚やばいな
Today, we're going the usual route at Nonhoi Park.
今日はのんほいパークの王道
We're focusing on the zoo area.
動物園ゾーンを中心に回っている
When I'm with the Literature Club members,
文芸部の連中と一緒に行動すると
trouble is to be expected, but...
トラブルがつきものだが
...today is going surprisingly smoothly.
今日は実にスムーズだ
Why is that?
なぜだ
If I had to take a guess...
いつもと違うところといえば…
Speaking of which, Yanami-san...
そういえば八奈見さん
You haven't eaten anything today, have you?
今日は何も食べてないよな
Is there some health problem?
お医者さんに止められてるとか？
Why would you think that?
なんでそうなるの？
I'm so healthy that even the doctor has given up on me!
お医者さんもサジを投げるくらい 健康でーす
Doesn't that mean it's too late?
それもう手遅れなんじゃないか？
But if Yanami hasn't eaten anything...
でも八奈見が何も食べてないと
I'm starting to feel a bit uneasy.
なんか不安になってくるな
What is this feeling?
なんだこの感情は
Are you really okay?
本当にいいのか
There are a lot of food trucks out on the main street.
中央の大通りに キッチンカーたくさん出てるぞ
Huh?
え
The main street...
大通り…
I think I'm good for today...
今日は…いいかな…
What's up, Yanami-sa—
どうした八奈見さ――
Stop, Nukkun. Come here!
ちょっとぬっくん こっち来て
Hey, don't pull me like that!
な、なに引っ張るなってよ
Look.
ほら
When we came here for the fake boyfriend thing...
こないだ偽彼氏の件で来た時
Over there by the canal.
あそこの水路のところで
Hakamada and Himemiya-san.
袴田（はかまだ）と 姫宮（ひめみや）さん
Seeing something like that would give you trauma.
あんなの見せられたら トラウマになるよ
It's not the time for food!
ご飯どころじゃないって
D-die!
し、死ね！
Is that really how it is?
そんなもんか？
But right after, she ate two servings of fried chicken.
でもあの直後 唐揚げ二人前食ってたぞ
There's a delay!
時間差（？）で来るんだよ
At the time, she was fine, but...
その時は大丈夫な気がしてたけど
How should I say it...
なんかこう
It's like tears suddenly start to flow out of nowhere...
ふとした時に 急に涙が出てくるっていうか
It's like it suddenly hits you...
膝に来るっていうか
Just like right now.
ちょうど今みたいな
Huh?
え？
Hey, are you okay?
おい大丈夫か？
Hey, Yakishio, I've got some candy.
や、焼塩 あめあるぞ
Nukumizu, just die!
ぬ、温水は死ね！
This is bad.
まずい
The atmosphere suddenly turned hellish.
一気に地獄みたいな空気になったぞ
We were having so much fun just a moment ago.
さっきまであんなに楽しそうだったのに
Why?
なぜだ
I'm... going for a run.
あたし… ちょっと走ってくるよ
Me too...
あたしもちょっと
I'm going to check on the sun bear.
マレーグマの顔を見てくる
It seems like they've both gone off somewhere.
なんか
I-it's your fault.
ぬ、温水が悪い
T-take responsibility.
せ、責任取れ
It's my fault...
俺のせい…
...I kind of feel that way too.
…な気もする
I'm not sure why, though.
なぜ俺のせいなのかは 分からんが
It looks like we've come to the Botanical Gardens while walking towards less crowded areas.
つい人の少ない方に向かって歩いてると 植物園に来ちゃうよな
I-I like botanical gardens, so I don't mind.
植物園好きだし
I feel calm because I can be alone.
な、なんか一人になれるから お、落ち着くし
So, was I in the way then?
じゃあ俺邪魔だったか？
I'll tolerate you for today.
今日はお前で我慢しとく
Komari seems to be in a good mood.
なんか小鞠（こまり）は 機嫌よさそうだな
Oh.
あれ
The bench over there is...
あそこのベンチは
S-sure, let's take a little break.
す、少し休んでいく
I see.
そっか
Uh, I'll-
えっと俺
Aren't you going to sit down?
す、座らないのか？
Ah
あ
Yes.
はい
I'll sit down.
座ります
Two wooden chairs placed side by side.
二つ並んで置かれた木の椅子
We sit next to each other, and silently look up at the trees around us.
俺たちは隣同士に座り
I-It's feels kind of weird, huh?
な、なんか不思議な気分だな
Weird?
不思議って？
W-We...
わ、私たち
A lot has happened since summer, but...
夏頃から色々あったけど
W-Well, somehow...
な、なんか
I'm able to talk like this now...
こんな風に話せるようになって
That's true.
そうだな
When we first met
初めて会った時
You used to call me 'Nukumizu-kun', didn't you?
小鞠なんか俺のこと
Ah
あ
Back then, you were scary and gave off a strange vibe.
あの時の温水
So, are you not scared of me now?
じゃあ今は怖くないのか？
Because you're you.
ぬ、温水だしな
And also...
そ、それに
And?
それに？
...because you're here with me.
ちゃ、ちゃんと一緒に
Yeah.
だな
The seniors, and Yanami and Yakishio too.
先輩たちとか
We'll stay with Komari from now on, too.
これからも小鞠と 一緒にいてくれるって
I must say, that was a good comment.
我ながらいいことを言った
I thought so, but...
つもりだったが
For some reason, Komari looks exasperated.
小鞠はなぜか 呆れたような視線を向けてくる
Eh
え
What?
なに？
That's the thing about you, Nukumizu.
そ、そういうとこだな 温水
Everyone says that, but...
みんなそれ言うけど
What do they mean by "that's the thing about you?"
そういうとこってどういうとこだよ？
Ah
あ
The two of you were here.
二人ともそこにいたんだ
Ah, Yakishio.
あ焼塩
Are you done with running?
走るのはもういいのか？
I'm all warmed up now.
体も温まったし
My head's starting to feel pleasantly light and fuzzy.
頭の中いい具合に ふわっとしてきたし
It's kind of addictive, you know?
なんかこれ癖になるんだよね
Isn't running bad for your body?
走るのって体に悪いんじゃない？
Are you okay?
大丈夫？
Oh!
おお
Everyone's gathered here, aren't they?
みんな集まってるじゃん
I was looking for you.
探したよ
Yanami-san... you're eating something again.
八奈見さん ってまたなんか食べてる
I bought some churros from the stand in front of the amusement park.
遊園地の前の売店で チュロス買ってきたんだよ
Here, Lemon-chan and Komari-chan, have a bite.
はい檸檬（れもん）ちゃんと 小鞠ちゃんも一口お食べ
Ha! Thanks, Yana-chan!
はぁ！八奈（やな）ちゃんありがとう
Oh, thank you.
あ、ありがとう
It seems that having food in her hands cheered Yanami up.
八奈見も食べ物を手にして 元気が出たらしい
I felt a bit relieved.
少しほっとした
Hmm?
ん？
Why are you staring like that?
どうしたのじっと見て
Do you want a bite too, Nukumizu-kun?
ひょっとして温水君も 一口食べたい？
No, you're already eating it...
いや食べかけは…
...No, I'm not hungry.
…じゃない お腹空いてないから
More importantly, the park is about to close.
それよりそろそろ閉園だぞ
Weren't we here today to take photos for the website?
あれ今日って ホームページの写真を撮りに来たんでしょ？
Nukumizu-kun, are you not taking any photos?
温水君撮んなくて大丈夫？
There's nothing too worry about.
それなら問題ない
I've already taken some good photos.
すでにいい写真が撮れたからな
Nukkun, when did you take that?
ぬっくんいつの間に撮ったの？
S-show it!
み、見せろ！
Hey, don't push!
あー押すなって
Look, I took a picture of the three of you from behind as you were entering Nonhoi Park.
ほら三人がのんほいパークに 入場するときの後姿を撮ったんだ
It gives off a nice vibe, like we're about to head out on an adventure.
なんかこれから行くぞって感じで いい雰囲気だろ
Huh?
え？
What's this?
これって
Ah, Nukkun, this...
あーぬっくんこれ…
S-sneak photography!
と、盗撮！
Huh?
え？
No, no, it's not like that at all!
いやいやそんなんじゃないって！
I can capture everyone's natural expressions like this, right?
気づかれずに撮った方が みんなの自然な表情が撮れるだろ
That's why I have to do it without anyone noticing.
だからバレないようにこっそりとだな
Isn't that called sneak photography?
それを盗撮って言うんじゃないかな？
N-Nukumizu even has a record of secretly taking pictures of me at the city library.
ぬ、温水は街中図書館でも わ、私を盗み撮りした前科がある
What? Those photos were taken secretly!?
え？あの写真盗撮だったの！？
Nukkun, that's not okay.
ぬっくんそれはダメだよ
If you want to do that, then take pictures of me.
そういうの撮りたいんだったら あたしを撮りなよ
Huh? Is that okay? Nukumizu-kun does that all the time, you know.
え？いいの？ 温水君盗撮魔だよ
Well, if it's Nukkun, I guess it's okay.
まあぬっくんならいいかなって
Do you want to do it too, Komari-chan?
小鞠ちゃんも一緒に撮ってもらう?
Huh? Th-that's way too grown-up a game.
え？そ、それは大人の遊びすぎる
I don't have a hobby of sneak photography.
俺に盗撮の趣味なんてないって
Come on, I'm going to take a proper one now, so everyone line up over there.
ほらちゃんとしたの 撮るからみんなそこに並んで
Hey, aren't you still being a bit sloppy?
ねえ相変わらず雑じゃない？
Yeah.
だね
Put a little more feeling into it!
もうちょっと感情込めようよ
Get arrested!
た、逮捕されろ！
Wow, these guys sure have a lot of demands.
はぁこいつら注文が多いな
It's almost closing time, so where should we take the photo?
もう閉園時間も 近いしどこで撮れば
Alright, I've made up my mind.
よし決めた
Everyone, follow me!
みんな俺についてきてくれ
Oooh.
おおおおおお
So,
っで
We are in front of Non-chan and Hoi-kun's place.
のんちゃん・ほいくんの前なんだ
It's right on the way home, after all.
だってちょうど帰り道だし
If we go away from the station, it'll be a pain to come back.
駅と反対側行くと 戻るの大変だろ
Nukkun, you're as consistent as ever.
ぬっくん相変わらずだね
R-reflect on your actions.
は、反省しろ
No, no, it's not just about being a pain.
いやいや 面倒ってだけじゃないんだ
My phone's battery is about to die.
スマホのバッテリーが切れそうだし
I want to get it over with quickly.
早く済ましちゃいたくてさ
Didn't your phone's battery die the last time we came here too?
あれこの間来た時も スマホのバッテリー切れてなかった？
It seems like my battery drains unusually fast whenever I go out lately.
最近遊びに出た時に限って やけに減りが早いんだ
It's still pretty new, though.
まだ新しいんだけどな
If you're taking the picture, do it quickly.
と、撮るなら早くしろ
Oh, right.
おっとそうだな
Okay, line up the three of you there.
はい そこに3人並んで
Don't get in Non-chan and Hoi-kun's way.
のんちゃん・ほいくんを邪魔しないように
Hold on a second.
ちょっと待って
Nukkun, aren't you joining in?
ぬっくん入んないの？
Huh?
え
There's no point in me joining in, right?
俺なんて入っても仕方ないだろ
That's not what I meant.
そういうことじゃないんだよ
When we're about to take a group photo...
集合写真を撮ろうって時に
Do you really think we're the kind of cold people who would leave you out?
私たちが君を仲間外れにするような 冷たい人間だって思ってるの？
Yeah, Nukkun, you should join in too.
そうそうぬっくんも入んなよ
Oh, be grateful.
あ、ありがたく思え
Uh, well then...
え ああ じゃあ…
How do you set the self-timer again?
セルフタイマーって どうやってかけるんだっけ
Hurry up!
はーやーくー
Don't rush me.
急かさないでくれ
Is the timer set like this?
あれタイマーってこれで セットされてるんだっけ
Huh, only three seconds left?
えあと3秒？
Oh, I totally missed it.
あ 全然間に合わなかったぞ
Hey, is it good?
ねえどんなの撮れた?
Let me see, let me see!
見せて見せて
Oh, it turned out really well.
ああ よ、よく撮れてる
I'm totally not in the shot.
俺全然間に合ってないじゃん
I'm cut off in the corner.
隅っこに見切れてるし
We need to retake it.
撮り直さないと
Huh?
って あれ？
The battery's dead.
バッテリー切れた
Well, I guess that last photo will have to do.
じゃあさっきの写真で終わりだね
Both of you looked cute in the photo.
2人とも可愛く撮れてたよ
You looked cute too, Yana-chan.
八奈ちゃんも可愛かったよ
Oh, wait, is that really okay for me?
あ 待って俺はあれでいいの？
Are we really putting that on the website?
あれをホームページに載せるの？
J-just be grateful you're even in the picture.
う、映ってるだけありがたく思え
Ehhh...
えぇぇ
But if I keep complaining, it'll seem like I really want to be in the photo...
でもこれ以上ごねるのは なんか映りたがってるみたいで恥ずかしいな
Well, if everyone else is okay with it, then so am I.
まぁみんながいいなら それでいいか
Well, since it's almost time for the train, shall we head back?
じゃ電車の時間も近いし そろそろ帰ろうか
Ah
あ
Wait a moment, I'm going to buy juice from that vending machine.
そこの自販機で ジュース買うからちょっと待って
I really do live for this one drink, don't I?
やっぱこの一杯のために 生きてるよね
By the way, do you have enough money today?
そういえば今日はお金大丈夫？
It won't be like last time, right?
こないだみたいなことはないよね？
Nukumizu-kun, I'm not the same person I used to be.
温水君 私は昔の私じゃ――
I'm a slightly more grown-up and wise Yanami-chan.
少し大人になった 賢い八奈見ちゃんなのです
Saying you're smart makes you sound kind of dumb, doesn't it?
自分で賢いって言うのって バカっぽいよな
Today, I've already checked the contents of my wallet.
今日の私は 財布の中身をちゃんと確認済み
I even accounted for the small change, and with that juice I just bought, I used up all my money perfectly.
小銭もきっちり計算に入れて 今のジュースで所持金は綺麗に使い切ったの
Not even a single yen left?
1円残らず？
That's right! Isn't it amazing?
そう1円残らずすごくない？
Even the sales tax was spot on.
消費税もぴったりだよ
That's impressive, but...
それはすごいけど
Can you afford the train fare?
帰りの電車賃大丈夫?
Huh?
え
Did you buy a ticket?
切符買った？
The train fare?
電車賃？
Huh?
え？
Oh, right.
そっか
I forgot about the train fare back.
帰りの電車賃忘れてた
Um...
えっと
Should I lend you some money?
お金貸そうか?
No, no, I can't borrow any more money from you...
いやいやこれ以上 温水君に恥をさらせないよ
Komari-chan!
小鞠ちゃん！
I only have enough money left for the train ride home, too.
私も帰りの電車賃しか残ってない
Huh?
え
You don't have to hold back.
遠慮しなくていいって
You can pay me back whenever.
ある時払いでいいから
I-I'm fine, really.
だ、だ、大丈夫だって
Lemon-chan
檸檬ちゃん
Yeah, leave it to me, Yana-chan.
うん あたしに任せて八奈ちゃん
Oh, thanks!
ありがとう！
Having friends really is the best, isn't it?
やっぱ持つべきものは友達だね
Count on me!
頼りにしてよ！
Let's start running then!
じゃあ早速走ろっか
Huh?
え？
I didn't run enough today, so this is really getting me pumped!
いや今日は走り足りなかったから テンション上がるな！
No, no, if you could just lend me enough for the train fare.
いやいや あの電車賃貸してくれれば…
It's fine, we can just run.
大丈夫走ればいいから
Y-yes.
は、はい
Nukumizu...
温水
Ah.
ああ
Then Komari and I will take the train—
じゃあ俺と小鞠は電車で―
Since we're all here, why not everyone run?
せっかくだし4人で走ろっか
It'll be done in no time!
パーッと走ればすぐだって
I-I-I'll take the train.
わ、わ、私は電車で
I'll give you a piggy back if you need it!
いざとなったら私が おぶってあげるから
Alright, let's go!
はい 行くよ！
Alright, I'll leave Komari to you then.
じゃ、じゃあ小鞠は任せた
I don't want to get in the way.
俺は邪魔しちゃ悪いから
You can't go home alone.
ダメだよ一人で帰っちゃ
I'll take care of Komari-chan.
あたしが小鞠ちゃんを お世話するから
Nukkun, give Yana-chan a piggyback if she gets tired.
ぬっくんは八奈ちゃんが 疲れたらおぶるんだよ
What? She's too heavy...
え？重いから無理
Nukumizu-kun?
温水君？
No! That's what I was saying, but not like that!
ああいやそういう意味だけど そうじゃなくて！
If I need carry someone, it should be Komari.
背負うなら小鞠の方が
D-
し―
Die!
死ね！
No, I meant Komari is lighter!
違うって 小鞠の方が軽いから！
Not that Yanami-san is heavy!
いや八奈見さんが 重いって意味じゃなくて
Huh?
あれ？
Did you rebound recently?
最近ちょっとリバウンドした
I haven't!
してませんけど！
Every year around this time, I'm in a growth spurt.
毎年この時期は成長期なんです
So, Yana-chan did gain weight.
やっぱ八奈ちゃん太ったんだ
Then, let's run!
ちょうどいいじゃ走ろうよ
Wait, hold on a second.
え、ちょっと待って
If I start running, my knees make a cracking sound.
先走ると膝がパキパキいうから
That's so cool!
なにそれかっこいいじゃん
Nukkun and Komari-chan, you're coming too!
はいぬっくんも 小鞠ちゃんも行くよ！
I'll take the train.
俺は電車で
This is all your fault, Nukumizu-kun.
こうなったのも温水君のせいでしょ
I won't let you run away by yourself!
自分だけ逃げようなんて 許さないんだけど
Don't try to dodge responsibility.
せ、責任から逃げるな
It's not my fault at all.
全然俺のせいじゃないだろ
Hey, wait, don't push my back!
あ、ちょ、背中を押すなって！
Nukumizu-kun...
温水君…
Take responsibility!
責任取れ！！